(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
#尾丸ポルカ3D
尾丸ポルカ 3Dお披露目
1月10日 日曜日 20:00~
#OmaruPolka3D
Omaru Polka 3D Debut
January 10th (Sun) 8:00 PM~
ハイ！
Hi!
ミュートじゃないわ！
I'm not on mute!
ポルカおるよ！
Polka is here!
ハハッ！
Haha!
どうだったゾウ？
How was the elephant?
やばくない？
Isn't it crazy?
謎のリアルさ。
That mysterious realism.
ヤッホー、ポルカおるよ！
Yahoo, Polka is here!
イエーイ！
Yay!
もう、昨日までのすべては伏線だったんだよ。
Everything up until yesterday was foreshadowing.
これがポルカのサーカステント。
This is Polka's circus tent.
おまるさ...
Omarusa...
おぬま、おんま、おま、おまるさポルカサーカスへようこそ！
Onuma, Omma, Oma, welcome to Omarusa Polka Circus!
イエーイ、どうも！
Yay, hello!
ホロライブ五期生、尾丸ポルカです。
I'm Hololive 5th Gen, Omaru Polka.
見てる、見てる、見てる？
Can you see me? Can you see me?
あれ？
Huh?
あ、あ、そう言う感じなんだ。
Oh, oh, I see how it is.
ど、どこにそのカーテン配置されてるの？
Wh-where is that curtain placed?
あ、ありがとうございます、どうも。
Oh, thank you very much, hello.
あのいつもね、見てくださってありがとうございます。どうも。
Thank you for always watching. Hello.
イエーイ！
Yay!
イエ、なんかあれだね。
Yay, it feels like...
テレビっぽいな。ハハハッ！
It's like TV. Hahaha!
よろしくお願いします。
Nice to meet you.
あの、さっそくなのですが、
Well, straight to the point,
どうですか、この、この何？
how is this, this what?
身体。
Body.
ハハッ！いつも多分見えてないと思うんだけど、
Haha! You probably don't usually see it,
どうなんだろう。
so what do you think?
あら、あら、あら。
Oh, oh, oh.
ちょっとね、カメラをね、そう。
Just a bit, let's get the camera, yeah.
あの、あれ、なんだっけ。
Um, that, what was it?
動く、動く。なんかアップにするやつ。
It moves, it moves. The thing that zooms in.
アップにするやつ。
The zoom-in thing.
アップにするやつ、カメラください。
Zoom-in camera, please.
魔法のカメラ。
The magic camera.
お、お、うわ、近っ！
Oh, oh, whoa, it's close!
え、ちょっと待って、恥ずかしい、恥ずかしい。
Wait, just a second, it's embarrassing.
恥ずかしいんですけど。
It's really embarrassing.
やば。
This is crazy.
ヤッホー、見てる？
Yahoo, are you watching?
はい。いひ、いひ。
Yes. Hehe, hehe.
いひ。
Hehe.
あの、じっくり見て。
Um, look closely.
あ、そんな、あ、そうそうそう。
Ah, such, ah, yeah yeah yeah.
あー、もうちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ。
Ah, oh, wait wait wait.
ヤッホー、見てる？
Yahoo, are you watching?
やった、いひ。
Yay, hehe.
じゃあ、あの、ほら、
Then, look,
このあたりとか。
around here.
何が気にかかるだい、君たちは。
What are you guys curious about?
おおっ！
Ooh!
え、ねえ、このおへそすごくない？おへそ。
Hey, isn't this belly button amazing?
どう？
What do you think?
お腹、今日冷えてないよ。
My stomach isn't cold today.
大丈夫だよ。
It's fine.
近いな。
It's close.
めっちゃ近くまで、ちょ、あの、やっぱりやめよう。
It's really close, wait, let's stop this.
やっぱり恥ずかしいからやめようか。
It's embarrassing after all, so let's stop.
え、ほら、後ろとか。
Eh, look, from behind.
どう？意外と見たことない。
How is it? You've probably never seen it.
フンッ！フンフンフンフンフンッ！
Humph! Humph humph humph humph humph!
リボンもこうなってまーす。
The ribbon is like this too.
ないんだよね、ポルカの後ろ姿。
You don't usually see Polka's back.
付け根こうなってるんだよ。
The base looks like this.
これ着るときなんかこうジャーってして大変。
It's hard to put it on, it's a pain.
はい。
Yes.
あ、ありがとう、可愛い。ありがとう。
Ah, thank you, cute. Thank you.
いや、初めて見たでしょ、そうですよ。
Well, it's your first time seeing it, right?
なかなか、なかなかそうね。
It's quite something.
え、何？下から？
Eh, what? From below?
あ、え、おや、おい！
Ah, eh, wait, hey!
それはダメ！
That's not allowed!
いや、やめて。
No, stop.
あ、あ、ちょ、ちょ... おい！
Ah, ah, wait, wait... Hey!
おい！おい！
Hey! Hey!
やめて、ちょ、やめて。
Stop it, wait, stop it.
バンバンバン、ババンバン！
Ban ban ban, ba-ban-ban!
やめてよ、バンバン。
Stop it with the 'bans'.
あ、ありがとう。あーびっくりした。
Ah, thank you. Phew, that was a surprise.
しっぽ見る？あともうちょっと。
Want to see my tail? Just a bit more.
あの、ここでしか見られへん。
Um, you can only see it here.
えい、えい、えい、えい、えい、えい、えい、えい、えい、えい、えい。
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
尾丸ポルカの「お」はね、お尻が丸いから尾丸なんだよ。
The "O" in Omaru Polka stands for "round butt," that's why it's Omaru.
あの、寝る時丸まるんすわ。
Um, I curl up when I sleep.
こう、寝る時、こう丸まって...ギュッてなるから、こう、尾丸なわけ。
Like, when I sleep, I curl up like this... and get all compact, so that's why it's Omaru.
え？何？アホ毛？
Eh? What? My hair flick?
回んないよ。回んな、すま。
It doesn't spin. It won't spin, sorry.
ちょっと今回の技術は足りんかった、私の。私がね、これもっと回せるようになったら...
My skills weren't quite enough this time. If I get better at spinning this...
空も飛べるかもしれん。
I might even be able to fly.
もしかしたら、ホログラがやってくれるかもしれない。
Maybe Hologra will do it for me.
みんな、お問い合わせしよう。
Everyone, let's send in a request.
よし、これでいいだろ。
Alright, this should be fine.
え、これでよかった？
Wait, was this okay?
あ、回ってほしかった？
Ah, did you want me to spin?
ポルカが回るよ、じゃあ。ほら、これでいいだろ、ほら、私が回るからほら！
Then Polka will spin! Here, this is what you wanted, right? Look, I'm spinning!
ほら、これで満足か？ほら。
See? Are you satisfied now? Look.
よし、いいぞ。いいぞ。回ってる？
Alright, nice. Nice. Am I spinning?
どう？回ってる？あんま？
How is it? Am I spinning? Not really?
あんまかな？
Not really, I guess?
え？じゃあ、え、どうしよう。
Eh? Then, um, what should I do?
あ、なんかこれ、アーティストやん。
Ah, this is kind of like an artist.
あ、なんかすごいアーティストっぽくなってる今。
Ah, I look like a total artist right now.
おお...
Ooh...
え、何これ、パリコレ？
Wait, what is this, Paris Fashion Week?
すごくない？ホロコレ？出られる？
Isn't it amazing? HoloColle? Can I be in it?
魅惑なボディが、魅惑的な尾丸ポルカ。
The enchanting Omaru Polka with an enchanting body.
魅惑のボディが本当に魅惑的です。
This enchanting body really is enchanting.
え、こんなんで、酔っちゃう、ごめん、酔っちゃう。
Eh, with just this, you'll get drunk? Sorry, you'll get drunk.
それは耐性がなさすぎだろ。
You have way too little tolerance for that.
おい、おい、ビール買い！ビール買い！
Hey, hey, buy some beer! Buy some beer!
おい。
Hey.
あれ？
Huh?
あ、あの、ここです。ここです、ここですよ。
Ah, um, over here. Over here, I'm over here.
あ、あ、あ...はははは！
Ah, ah, ah... Hahaha!
ただいま。
I'm back.
ステージいいでしょ。すごくない？
The stage is great, right? Isn't it amazing?
いいでしょ。あれ、おかえり。
It's nice, right? Oh, welcome back.
ヤッホー。どう？
Yahoo! How is it?
えー、コメント、なんか見たいところある？
Hmm, comments, is there anything you want to see?
ふふふ、ほかのサーカスの雰囲気がすごい、え。
Hehehe, the atmosphere of the other circus is amazing... eh.
あとで見せたげるからちょっと待ってな。
I'll show you later, so just wait a bit.
ウインク、バチコン！うりゃい！
Wink, bam! Take that!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
鎖骨？
Collarbone?
え、なんかマニアックじゃない、それ。
Eh, isn't that a bit of a niche request?
見えるじゃん、これ、見えるでしょ、別に。
You can see it, look, you can see it anyway.
え？え？
Eh? Eh?
もっと、見せて...
Show us more...
後ろ？え？
The back? Eh?
なんか...え？な...
Something... eh? Wha...
普通にこれ恥ずかしいな。あ、ちょっと...
This is actually kind of embarrassing. Ah, wait a second...
いるよ、なんかいる、わあ！
There's something here, something's here, waah!
え？
Eh?
お前たち...
You guys...
お前たち、まさか...
You guys, don't tell me...
あ、来てくれたんか、ポルカのために。微動だにせんけどお前ら。
Ah, you came for me, for Polka. Even though you aren't moving an inch.
来てくれたんか。うちのお丸座員よ。
So you came. My Omaru-Zain.
マジこいつら...
Seriously, these guys...
あの、生きてる？生きてんのかなこいつら。え？
Um, are you alive? Are these guys alive? Eh?
ほら、ほら、ほら...
Look, look, look...
さて、ポルカどこにいるでしょうか？
Now then, where is Polka?
尾丸ポルカどこにいるでしょうか？
Where is Omaru Polka?
あ、わかるわこれ。
Ah, I can tell.
ははははは！
Hahahahaha!
離さんといて。
Don't leave me.
尾丸ポルカどこにいるでしょうか？
Where is Omaru Polka?
おるな。わかるな、これ。
There she is. I can tell.
え、すごい座員くん可愛いね。これ、なんか...
Eh, the Zain-kuns are so cute. This, somehow...
ちょっと足蹴にしちゃってる、足蹴に...ごめん、ごめん！踏んでない、踏んでない！
I'm kind of kicking them, kicking... Sorry, sorry! I'm not stepping on you, I'm not!
違う、違う、踏んでない、踏んでない！
No, no, I'm not stepping on you!
埋まった。
I'm buried.
咲いた。
I bloomed.
そっか。じゃあお前らよく来てくれた。
I see. Well, you guys did well to come.
ま、一応、これから始まるから、お前らよく見ておけ。
Well, for now, things are about to start, so you guys watch closely.
じゃ、解散。散れ、散れ！
Now then, dismissed. Scram, scram!
はははは！そんな解散の仕方、はははは！びっくりした。
Hahaha! What a way to dismiss them, hahaha! That surprised me.
なんかサプライズ出演かな？サプライズ解散に笑っちゃった。
Was that like a surprise appearance? The surprise dismissal made me laugh.
いい絵面よかったね。
That was a good shot.
まあ、というわけでね、ちょうど...まあ先日、フニフニフニャフニャでもね...
Well, anyway, just... well, the other day, even during the prep...
サーカステントとか作り終えたということで。
We finished building the circus tent and everything.
えー、サーカステント。こちら！ようやくね、みんなもね、迎え入れられたということで。
Um, the circus tent. This is it! We were finally able to welcome everyone.
テント、見せたいと思います。
I'd like to show you the tent.
さあ、まず、これどういう感じになってるかっていうのを、ちょっと見てほしいんだけど。
Now then, first, I want you to see what it's like in here.
おお！
Ooh!
これだよ、求めてたのは。
This is it, what I was looking for.
あそこにブランコがあってね。
There's a trapeze over there.
あそこにね、あのね、登るんよ。
I'm going to, you know, climb up there.
めぐりめぐり動かすのよ
Round and round, make it move.
あー、いいわー！すげー！
Ah, this is great! Incredible!
トランポリンもある！トランポリンもある！トランポリンもある！
There's a trampoline too! A trampoline! A trampoline!
あ、大砲もある。あそこに、入るんだよ誰か。
Oh, there's a cannon too. Someone's gonna go in there.
今度いれよう誰か。
Let's put someone in next time.
え、すごい、いいですね！
Whoa, incredible, this is nice!
やったー！あははは！
Yay! Hahaha!
これひとつ夢叶っちゃったんだよなぁ。
One of my dreams just came true.
やべ。
Whoa.
どうする？え、え、どうしよう。
What should I do? Uh, uh, what now?
あ、やべ、見られた！あははは！
Oh, shoot, I was seen! Hahaha!
すげー！ねぇ、見て見て、やばいやばい。
Incredible! Hey, look, look, this is crazy.
ステージもちゃんとある。
There's a proper stage too.
ライトもある。え、でもさ、なんか、なんだろう。
There are lights too. But, like, what else...
これさ、どう思う？
What do you think of this?
なんかまだ、何かがまだ、足りない気がする。
I feel like something, something is still missing.
いや、何かな、何が足りないんだろうなー。
I wonder what it is, what could be missing?
うーん...。
Hmm...
なんか、もう一つ、加えるとしたら...。
If I were to add one more thing...
ふんふん、振りが下手だな。
Hmm, my choreography is bad.
ライオン火の輪... 違う違う違う！
A lion jumping through fire... No, no, no!
まあ観客もそうなんだけど、今日はまだお披露目だから！
Well, the audience too, but today is still just the debut!
えっと、なんて言うんだっけ、プレオープン、プレサービス。
Umm, what do you call it, pre-open, pre-service.
というわけで、さあ！行きます！
And so, here we go!
このサーカスの変身を！
The transformation of this circus!
第二形態？用意、ドーン！
Second form? Ready, go!
Welcome!
ポルカサーカスの初めてのお客様！
First guests of the Polka Circus!
やあやあ、お待たせしました。
Hey there, thanks for waiting.
とてもハッピーな動物たち。
Very happy animals.
ユカイでかわいい。
Amusing and cute.
魔界の子からエルフまで。
From denizens of hell to elves.
TV SHOWじゃない。
This isn't a TV show.
ここだけのサーカス。
A circus found only here.
It's Show time!!
なにがみたい？
What do you want to see?
どんなことでもしてあげる。
I'll do anything for you.
私は座長、その名も尾丸ポルカ。
I am the ringmaster, Omaru Polka.
ぜったい笑顔にさせちゃうぜ、スマイル！
I'll definitely make you smile, SMILE!
それでは最後まで。
So then, until the very end...
付き合ってもらうからな！
I'll have you stay with me!
Are You Ready?
さあさあ近くにおいで。
Come on, come closer.
きっと誰もが仰天。
Surely everyone will be amazed.
奇想天外なショーの始まりさ。
The start of an extraordinary show.
グッと惹かれるでしょ？
You're captivated, aren't you?
おっと！押さないでね。
Whoops! Don't push now.
それでは準備OKですか？
So then, are you ready?
愉快な動物たち、玉乗りピエロ。
Amusing animals, clowns on balls.
ハラハラドキドキしちゃうでしょ！
It'll get your heart racing, won't it!
真っ赤な枠くぐらせ。
Leaping through a bright red hoop.
綱渡りして。
Walking the tightrope.
ちょっとくらいのドジなんてご愛嬌よ。
Being a bit clumsy is just part of the charm.
Come on! Light up!
とっておきのライブ。
A special live performance.
ボーッとしてないで。
Don't just stand there dazed.
さあもっと！手を叩こう！
Come on, more! Let's clap our hands!
ほらほら着いておいで。
Hey, hey, follow along.
目も回るようなサーカス。
A circus that'll make your head spin.
きっとここだけだよ。
Surely it's only here.
ホログラムみたい。
Like a hologram.
キラキラ奇跡が踊る。
Sparkling miracles dance.
いつかは世界中を。
Someday, the whole world...
虜にしちゃうぞ。
I'll make it captive.
楽しい！
So fun!
2番もよろしくお願いします！
Second verse coming up, please enjoy!
うーん、明日の演目は。
Hmm, tomorrow's program...
どうしようかな。
What should I do?
屋根裏で秘密の作戦会議さ。
A secret strategy meeting in the attic.
いっぱいの観客席が。
A full audience area.
アッと驚くような。
Will be surprised.
とびきりのショーを見せましょう。
I'll show you an extraordinary show.
思い付いたら。
When I get an idea.
ジッとしてられない。
I can't sit still.
団員を引き連れて。
Taking the troupe along.
Let's go!
ねえ、あれがやりたい！
Hey, I want to do that!
これもやりたい！
I want to do this too!
どうして時間って足りないの？
Why isn't there enough time?
うーん、なんでだろう。
Hmm, I wonder why.
なんで時間は足りなくなってしまうんだ。
Why does time always run out?
もっと、もっと！
More, more!
みんなの声が聞きたい！
I want to hear everyone's voices!
よろしくお願いします！
Please!
行くぞー！
Let's go!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
椅子ジャンプ！
Chair jump!
ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey!
ちゃんと手振っとるか！
Are you waving your hands properly!
ポルカおるぜー！
Polka's right here!
上手くいかなくって。
When things don't go well.
空回りってばかりで。
And I'm just spinning my wheels.
少し落ち込んじゃう日もあるけれど。
There are days when I feel a bit down.
見ててね。
Watch me, okay.
大丈夫いつまでも。
I'll be fine, forever.
クヨクヨしてらんないし。
I can't keep moping around.
顔を上げて。
Lift your head.
今日のステージがほら。
Look, today's stage.
ねえ、待ってるのさ。
Hey, it's waiting.
行くぞー！ポルカおるか？
Let's go! Is Polka here?
ポルカおるんか？
Is Polka here?
ポルカ歌うか？
Will Polka sing?
ポルカおるか？
Is Polka here?
ポルカ終わるか？
Will Polka finish?
ポルカおるか？
Is Polka here?
おーらーいよー！
Alright!
ポルカおるんか？
Is Polka here?
ポルカおるか？
ポルカ歌うか♪
Will Polka sing?♪
ポルカおるか？
Is Polka here?
ポルカ終わるか？
Is Polka finishing?
終わらない！
It's not over!
ポルカおるか！ポルカおるか！
Is Polka here! Is Polka here!
ポルカ踊るよー！
Polka's gonna dance!
強く　強く願うんだ
Strongly, strongly I wish
どんな夢だって　きっと　そうきっと　叶うはず
Any dream surely, yes surely, should come true
何も怖くない
I'm not afraid of anything
みんなの声は全部　ちゃんと届いてるよ
Everyone's voices are all properly reaching me
さぁ新しい次元　新しい舞台へ
Now to a new dimension, to a new stage
もっと　さぁもっと　突き進もう
More, now more, let's push forward
まだまだついておいで
Still, still, keep following me
笑い転げちゃうサーカス
A circus where you'll roll with laughter
絶対ここだけだよ
It's definitely only here
初めての仲間　景色に心も踊る
First time friends, my heart dances at the scenery too
今にも世界中を　虜にしちゃうから
Because I'm about to captivate the whole world
目を離しちゃダメだぞ
Don't take your eyes off me
普通に... 普通に...
I... I...
泣きそうになった。
almost cried normally.
ありがとうございました、ホログラムサーカスでした。
Thank you very much, that was Hologram Circus.
ポルカのね、オリジナル曲になっております。
It's my original song.
この前もね、MVが公開されたんですが
The MV was released just the other day,
後ろで流してもらえながら、被せてもらえながら...
and having it play behind me while I sing over it...
やっぱ、躍動感あるとあれやな。
After all, with a sense of dynamism, it's something else.
もう、弾んでしまう。
My heart is just bouncing.
胸がホエホエって... ん？
My chest is throbbing... Hm?
弾んではいないな。弾んではいないな。よし。
It's not bouncing. It's not bouncing. Alright.
まぁ、自分を痛めつけてこそのパフォーマー。
Well, a performer is someone who pushes themselves.
そして、これを歌いきってからさらにパフォーマンスをするのが
And performing even more after singing this through...
尾丸ポルカ！
...is Omaru Polka!
そして尾丸ポルカ、ジャグリングに挑戦します！
And Omaru Polka will now challenge juggling!
ジャグリングに挑戦！
Challenging juggling!
はぁ... いけるかなこれ... どうなんだろう
Whew... I wonder if I can do this... I wonder...
ジャグリングって... あの、色んな種類がありましてね。
juggling... You see, there are various kinds.
まぁ箱とかね、ステッキとか色々あるんですけど。はい。
Like boxes, sticks, there are many. Yes.
というわけで、こちら！まずは...
So, here it is! First...
ステッキ！ジャジャン！
Sticks! Ta-dah!
これ見て見て見て、ちゃんとポルカの...
Look at this, look, look, it's properly Polka's...
あれ... うわーもうね、ちゃんとステッキの柄になっとるんよ。
Oh... Wow, it's actually got the stick pattern on it.
この持ち手の部分。
This handle part.
おー、ええやんけ。ええ仕事するやんけ。
Oh, not bad. Good job.
ちょっ、こっ、こうか。
Wait, like this.
どうや？見える？
How is it? Can you see?
あーいいですね、いい仕事してますねぇ。
Ah, nice. You're doing a great job.
さあ、まずは２本。
Now, first, two.
大丈夫、まずは２本。落ち着いて。これは多分普通の人でも出来るはず。
It's okay, first two. Calm down. Anyone should be able to do this.
いくぞー！
Here I go!
そうなんだよ。そういうこともあるんだよ。
That's how it is. Things like that happen.
まぁ余裕でしたね。
Well, that was easy.
あの、ちょっと悲しいんで、失敗したら「カチャーン」ってしてくれます？
Um, it's a bit sad, so if I fail, could you play a "clatter" sound?
よし行くぞー！
Alright, here I go!
ほいっ、どいっ！
Hopp! Whoops!
見ないでー！見ないでー！
Don't look! Don't look!
ほっ！
Hopp!
いやまだいける、まだいける。まだ３本目を隠し持っているから、私は。
No, I can still do it. I still have a 3rd one hidden.
３本目を出せばもう完璧だよ。
It'll be perfect once I bring out the 3rd one.
ここで３本。２本勝つ、勝ち！いくぞ！
Three here. I'll win with two, win! Let's go!
違う違う違う！終わらないで！違うー！
No, no, no! Don't end! Nooo!
終わらないで！何でそういうことするのー！？もう！
Don't end! Why are you doing that?! Geez!
あ、分かった。ちょっとさ、
Oh, I get it. Hey,
ステッキくんさ、こうさ、やるからさ、ちょっと、こういう感じで...
Stick-kun, I'll do this, so just, like this...
よーし行きます、それでは行きます、はい！
Alriiiight, here goes. Here we go, yes!
お、ほら、見て見て見て！ほら！ほら！ほら！ほら！
Oh, look, look, look! See! See! See! See!
どう、どう、どう？
How is it? How is it?
もうちょっと、もうちょっと大振りで行こう、大振りで。おお、完璧！
A bit more, let's go with bigger swings. Oh, perfect!
え？
Eh?
今え？何、曲も止まっ... え？
Eh? Did the music just stop... Eh?
ジャグリングに挑戦！
Challenge: Juggling!
ありがとね、ステッキ君。本当に。
Thank you, Stick-kun. Truly.
ステッキ君がいい仕事してくれるんですよ。
Stick-kun is doing a great job, you see.
あ、分かった！もうちょっと...
Ah, I get it! Just a bit more...
多分いけるわこれ。分かった、行きます！
I think I can do this! Alright, here I go!
もう一回ならいける気がする。
I feel like I can do it if I try one more time.
最後、ラストチャレンジ！いこう！
The final, last challenge! Let's do this!
行くぞ...行くぞ！
Here I go... Here I go!
おらっと！おらっぱい！おっしゃい！
Hah! There! Hah! Yes! Alright!
あ、いいやん！うまい、うまい、うまい！うまい！
Ah, looking good! I'm a natural! I'm so good! I'm great!
え、超上手じゃん！すごい、すごい！え、うまい、うまい！なになに？すごい、すごいうまいうまい！
Wait, I'm super talented! Wow, wow! Wow, I'm so good! What is this? This is amazing!
今のはどうでしたか？判定。
How was that just now? Give me a rating.
みんな...あ、だめ？
Everyone... Ah, it's a fail?
ああ...何度でも終わらせに掛かる。
Aah... They're trying to end it no matter what.
あれ？だめでしたかね？どうでした？
Huh? Was that no good? How was it?
え？あ！違います！違いますよ！あの...曲が欲しかったとかそういうわけ...あ。
Eh? Ah, no! That's not it! I mean... it's not like I wanted background music or anything... Ah.
カットイン。尾丸ポルカ3Dお披露目
Cut-in. Omaru Polka 3D Debut!
はい、というわけで、ここまでので楽しかったという方は、
Alright then! If you've enjoyed it so far...
ハッシュタグ尾丸ポルカ3Dで呟いてください！
...please tweet with the hashtag #OmaruPolka3D!
や、どうでしたジャグリング？
So, how was the juggling?
どうですか？じゃ、あ、すごい、トレンド入りも乗ってくれてるということで、本当にトレンディーな尾丸ポルカよろしくお願いします！
How was it? Oh, wow... I'm even trending! Please continue to support the trendy Omaru Polka!
さ、ジャグリングできたよね？今のは。あれダメ？怪しい？どっちかな？
Well, I pulled off the juggling, didn't I? Just now. Was that a fail? Or was it 'sus'? Which one?
ちょっとダメ判定かなこれ。うーん。
I guess that counts as a 'fail' rating. Hmm.
じゃ分かった。分かった、ちょっと待って。提案が一つある。
Alright, I've got it. I've got it, wait a second. I have a suggestion.
うちのサーカスへまだあるんだ、道具。
Our circus still has more props.
そう、それは...
Yes, and that would be...
玉乗りに挑戦！
Challenge: Ball Balancing!
玉乗り！
Ball Balancing!
やはりね、玉に乗ってコロコロコロコロと進むのが、やっぱ分かりやすいでしょみんなにも。
After all, getting on a ball and rolling around is the easiest thing for everyone to understand.
一番分かりやすいじゃん！一番分かりやすいっしょ！
It's the most straightforward! The easiest to get, right?!
ということで今日はこの玉を持ってくるわじゃあ。
So, I'm going to go and get the ball now.
ちょっと持ってくる。勝手に持ってきていいのかなこれ？運んじゃっていいやつかな？
I'll be right back with it. I wonder if it's okay for me to just take it? Is it something I'm allowed to carry out?
ちょっと...玉君...なんて付けよう。玉君...あ、いてくれた、いてくれた。
Wait... Ball-kun... What should I call him? Ball-kun... Oh, there he is, there he is.
この...この...今運んでおります。ぐぬう！
This... This... I'm currently moving it. Hnnngh!
いや、ちょっと小さいように見えるかもしれないけど、これ遠近...遠近...遠近法で...
Now, it might look a bit small, but that's just because of perspective... perspective... perspective...
めっちゃ大きいから。ナイス！これめっちゃ大きいから。
it's actually really big! Nice! It's super huge.
これに乗ってコロコロと転ばれば、ちょっとサーカスかなって。どうかな？
If I get on this and roll around, it'll really feel like a circus. What do you think?
まあ判断は...あ！ダメだよそのカメラは！
Well, the verdict is... Ah! Not that camera angle!
判断は任せた。乗ったぞ私は玉に。行くぞ！
I'll leave the verdict to you. I've successfully mounted the ball. Here I go!
おっしゃ！行くぞ！おっしゃ！
Alright! Let's go! Alright!
おれ...よいしょ...あれ、だめだ。なんで？いや...とと...
There... whoa... hup... wait, it's not working. Why? Whoa... whoa...
こうやっていくんだよ、こうやって。分かるか？ほら。
This is how you do it, like this. See? Look.
一番...一番分かりやすいちびっ子向け...え？なんで？ちょっと待って、その悲しいカメラの視点やめて！
The most... the most straightforward thing for kids... Eh? Why? Wait, stop with that pitiful camera angle!
これ一番分かりやすいでしょ？ほらほら、こうやって...こうやっていくんだよって。こうやって、こうやって。
This is the easiest to understand, isn't it? Look, look, you go like this... this is how it's done. Like this, like this.
なんでこんなに疲れてるんだ？うおー！
Why am I so exhausted? Whoa!
いける、まだいける。お前と私の絆なら...いけるぞ！
I can do it, I can still do it. If it's our bond... then we can do this!
よっしょ。あの、じゃちょっとゆっくりここで...ふう...はは。よっしょ。
Alright. Um, let's take it slow here... Phew... Haha. Okay.
今ね...え？何で怪しいって言ってるの？嘘。
Right now... Eh? Why are you all saying it's 'sus'? No way.
ちなみにこの初めて見る人には分かんないと思うけど、この「サス」っていうのはね、怪しいなって言ってるみんな怪しいなって言ってる。
By the way, for people seeing this for the first time, you might not know, but 'sus' (ayashii) means everyone thinks it's suspicious.
怪しくないだろこれ全然。ほら！ほら！
This isn't suspicious at all! Look! Look!
え、うまい！やばい！めっちゃ上手くない？どうですか？これ判定お願いします。
Wow, I'm good! This is crazy! Aren't I super talented? How's this? Please give me a rating.
え？じー今帰ってきてるんだよ。どうかな？上手くない？ほらほらほらほらほら...
Eh? I-I'm on my way back now. How about it? Aren't I good? Look, look, look, look, look...
あ、上手いなこれ。あ、これ片足でもいけ...いけ...いけ...
Ah, I'm actually good at this. Oh, I can even do this on one leg... I can... I can...
おう！どういう...どういう...ちょっと...え？だめ全然？だめ？だめかな？上手いでしょちょっとこれ。よっしょ。なかなか。これはさすがに。
Whoa! What's... what's... wait... Eh? Is it totally no good? No? Is it bad? I'm pretty good at this, though. Alright. Not bad. As expected of me.
ねー！
Hey!
カッコいいでしょ！
I'm cool, right?
どうだ？どう？
How is it? Well?
どうだ？
How is it?
え？
Eh?
なるほど。
I see.
あ、じゃ、わかった。玉の上でジャグリングするわ。
Ah, okay, I get it. I'll juggle on top of the ball.
ういしょ！あははは！
Whoa! Ahahaha!
玉くん！
Tama-kun!
玉くん、楽しいことになっちゃった。
Tama-kun, things have gotten interesting.
大丈夫かな？元気？
Are you okay? Feeling well?
いこいこ。大丈夫よ、怪我してない？
There, there. It's okay, you're not hurt?
平気？
You okay?
大丈夫、一緒に行こうね。はいはい。
It's okay, let's go together. Yes, yes.
よしよし。はいはいはいはい。
There, there. Yes, yes, yes, yes.
よし！これでいいやろ。
Alright! This should do it.
ふー。
Phew.
うっしゃ！
Alright!
あ...
Ah...
ねぇ、乗り方が難しいんだけど！
Hey, getting on is hard!
あの...か...負けない...負けない...
Um... won't... won't lose...
負けない、負けないぞ！
I won't lose! I won't lose!
は！よいしょ！
Hah! Yoisho!
立てた！
I'm up!
えっと、やるか。
Um, shall we do this?
あの...あの...あの...あの...あの...
Um... um... um... um... um...
やります。
I'm doing it.
もう、カメラ引いちゃって！できるから今！
Camera, pull back! I can do it now!
ほら！ほら！ほら！ほら！ほら！
See! See! See! See! See!
よし...こら...ちょ...
Al- alright... wait... a bit...
うまい、うまい、うまい！いいよ、いいよ！
I'm good! I'm good! It's going well!
あれ、私マジックの人？マジックの人なのかな？
Wait, am I... am I a magician?
こっちも持って...こうこう、そうそうそう。
Hold this one too... like this... yes, yes.
うまいね！あ、うまい、うまい！
You're good! Ah, good, good!
スティッキくんもだんだん動きがわかって...こうさ、こう...あ、そうそうそう！あ、いいね！
The stick's movements are getting clearer too... like this... ah, right, right! Ah, nice!
なんで？！
WHY?!
は...そっか...だめだ...
Hah... I see... It's no use...
今の...今の見てた？
That... did you see that just now?
どうだった？
How was it?
ご感想聞かしてよ。
Let me hear your thoughts.
ん？
Hmm?
後で反省会？
After-party later?
屋根裏大集合？
Attic meeting?
うん。
Yeah.
わかった。
I see.
あ、客に尻を向け...あ、すみませんすみません。
Ah, I turned my back on the audience... sorry, sorry.
財にまさか諭されるとは、客に。
I never thought I'd be scolded for showing my back to the audience.
客に尻を向けるなって。
They told me not to turn my back on the guests.
言われると思わんだ。
I never thought I'd be told that.
はい。
Yes.
ただいま！
I'm back!
どうだった？
How was it?
後で屋根裏集合？
Attic meeting later?
呼び出し？
A calling-out?
きつ！マジかよ。
Harsh! Seriously?
あ、屋根裏で待っててもらってね、ありがとう。
Wait for me in the attic then. Thank you.
かわいいなお前らホントに。
You guys are really cute, honestly.
えっと...
Um...
ちょっと息もね、こちらの問題なんですが。
My breath is... well, it's my problem.
息を好きながらとあれなんで皆さんもどうかご着席ください。
While I catch my breath, please take a seat, everyone.
立ってないか。そっか。
Not standing? Oh, right.
じゃ、ちょっとポルカね、今日に向けて準備してきたものがあるから。
Well, Polka has something she prepared for today.
それを披露します。
I'll perform it now.
手紙を朗読します
Reading a letter
手紙を読ませていただきたいと思います。
I'd like to read a letter.
ちょっと久しぶりの朗読で。
It's been a while since I've read aloud.
少しちょっととちるかもしれないけど。
I might stumble a bit, but...
テンション下げて。
Calming down.
少女はおさない頃から人の目を気にする子でした。
As a young girl, she was always conscious of how others saw her.
お母さんのそばをはなれない子でした。
She was a child who wouldn't leave her mother's side.
いつも学校に行きたくないと泣いていました。
She would always cry, saying she didn't want to go to school.
ある日、パフォーマンスに心をうばわれました。
Then one day, her heart was captured by a performance.
人の目を気にしてしまう彼女でしたが、
She was someone who worried about what others thought,
舞台に立っているときだけは、
...but only when she was standing on stage...
全てを忘れて全力に出す事に
...could she forget everything...
夢中になれました。
...and lose herself in giving it her all.
とても幸せな場所を見つけたのです。
She had found a very happy place.
ホロライブにありがとうを伝えさせてください。
Please let me say thank you to Hololive.
あたたかく迎え入れてくれた先輩。
To the seniors who welcomed me so warmly.
不安な時にたくさん相談に乗ってくれて
I was so happy when you listened to all my worries...
うれしかったです。
...when I was anxious.
これからも、にぎやかな後輩だと思いますが、
I'm sure I'll continue to be a noisy junior, but...
これからも、にぎやかな後輩だと思いますが...
I think I'll continue to be a very lively junior...
どうかだんだん受け入れてくれるとうれしいです。
I'd be happy if you could gradually come to accept me.
まだ、多分変なやつだろうな！と思っていると思います。
You probably still think, "She's probably a weirdo!"
まあ、まだ、多分本当に賑やか、うるさいだけの変な奴だと思って...
Well, you probably still think I'm just a loud, noisy weirdo...
この前もすごい難しい凸待ちしちゃったし、そう思っていると思います。
Especially after that difficult collab I did recently.
それを変えていけるように、いっぱいお話ししたいです。
I want to talk a lot so that I can change that image.
そして、どんな時も、そばにいてくれた五期生。
And, my fellow 5th generation mates who have been by my side no matter what.
ここでは言えないくらいに、
So much that I can't even say it here,
泣いたり笑ったり、ぶつかりあったり、
crying, laughing, and clashing with each other...
短い間なのにたくさんの思い出をありがとうございます。
Thank you for so many memories despite the short time.
って言ったらなんか本当に何か終わっちゃうみたいだけど、終わんないよ、これからだよ。
Saying that makes it sound like it's over, but it's not! It's just the beginning.
そう、
That's right,
ここからまた一緒に歩いていきたいし、
I want to continue walking together from here on out.
みんなも色々な場所で忙しくなっているのを見ると、
When I see everyone getting busy in different places,
どこかさみしいようなうれしいようなです。
it's somehow both lonely and happy.
応援してくれているあなたへ。
To you who are supporting me.
本当にありがとう。
Thank you so much.
それしかないです、これ以上ないです。
That's all I have to say. Nothing else.
これからもよろしくお願いします。
I look forward to your continued support.
危なっかしいし、うるさいし、急に静かになるし感情のジェットコースター...
Dangerous, noisy, suddenly quiet, an emotional rollercoaster...
今の大丈夫だったかな？ってすぐ聞くけど...
I always ask, "Was that okay just now?"...
そう、そこ（画面の向こう）のお前だよ、聞くけど...
Yeah, I mean you behind the screen, I'll ask, but...
いっぱい寄りかかります。だから受け止めてください。
I'll lean on you a lot. So please support me.
その分、後悔させないです。
In return, I won't let you regret it.
そして見えないところで動いてくださっている人と、
And the people working behind the scenes,
これから交流する人、またよろしくお願いします。
and people I'll interact with in the future, please treat me well.
なんだかこれで終わりみたいな空気になってしまった... と思った瞬間に手紙に書いてあった言葉を忘れていた。
It feels like it's over now... At the moment I thought that, I forgot the words written in the letter.
なんだかこれで終わりみたいな空気になってしまった。
"It feels like it's over now."
気を取り直して、まだまだ彼女のサーカスは始まったばかり。
Pulling myself together, her circus has only just begun.
止まらず、想像をこえて、花を咲かせて、
Without stopping, beyond imagination, making flowers bloom,
海の向こうまで届けていきます。
I will deliver it even across the ocean.
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you very much.
というわけで、お手紙のコーナーでした！
And so, that was the letter segment!
なんかこいついつも手紙読んでんなって感じしない？
Don't you feel like she's always reading letters?
最近手紙読みがちだなぁポルカ。
Polka's been reading letters a lot lately.
もうすぐこいつやばいことして辞めるのかって感じのテンションだったけど、
It was like the tension of someone who's about to do something crazy and quit, but...
めちゃくちゃポルカは言いたいことを言ったんだよなぁ。
Polka really said what she wanted to say.
どうでした？
How was it?
あ、ありがとうございます。これからもこちらこそよろしくお願いします。
Ah, thank you. I also look forward to working with you.
ま、気を取り直して。
Well, pulling myself together.
さっきの、さっきの結果じゃまだまだ納得しない人がいるかもしれないからね。
There might be some people who aren't satisfied with the previous results.
もう一個演目残しております！挽回のチャンスいただけないでしょうか！
I have one more performance left! Could I have a chance to redeem myself?
こちらに挑戦させていただきます！拍手とコメントありがとうございます。頑張ります！行ってきます！
I'll take on this challenge! Thank you for the applause and comments. I'll do my best! Here I go!
というわけで、綱渡りに挑戦！
And so, the Tightrope Walking Challenge!
綱渡りに挑戦！
Tightrope Walking Challenge!
あ、もう一回いきます。せーの！綱渡りに挑戦！
Ah, I'll do it one more time. One, two! Tightrope Walking Challenge!
うまい。いや、あれ？綱渡りどこ？どこ綱？綱どこ？あれ、綱？
Good. Wait, huh? Where's the tightrope? Where's the rope? Rope where? Huh, rope?
綱渡りに挑戦！
Challenge the tightrope walk!
まって、なかなか...
Wait, it's quite...
初めての人が綱渡りしようとすると...
When a beginner tries to do a tightrope walk...
なんだろうね... やっぱ大変なことになっちゃう...
I don't know... It really ends up being a big deal...
ここ、上からピョーンってしちゃったら大変なことになっちゃうから...
If I jump from here, it'll be a disaster...
今日やっぱり、ここ、ここで見せられるのはこれなんだよな。
Today, what I can show you here is this.
これを見て始めたいなと思ったらやればいい。
If you see this and want to start, then go for it.
よし。
Alright.
これ実は、これも遠近法で、30メートルくらいあるから。
Actually, with perspective, this is about 30 meters high.
これ、大丈夫だから。
It's fine.
よし。
Alright.
ちょっと待って... ちゃんと、ほら。
Wait a sec... Look, properly.
ほら！ねえ、ちゃんと。
Look! See, properly.
こうなるからさ、な、何？
This is what happens, what... what?
落ちたら大変なんだよ。座員の群れだよ！
It's bad if I fall. It's a swarm of Zain!
あぶねえな。
That was close.
落ちたら座員の群れなんだからな！
If I fall, it's a swarm of Zain!
あ、ちょっと待って。ふぅ。
Oh, wait a sec. Whew.
よし。いける。
Alright. I can do this.
ちょっと、これちゃんと... わあ！
Wait, this properly... Whoa!
あの、パフォーマーたるもの、ちゃんと前を向いて。
As a performer, you must look forward.
いつも前を向いて...
Always look forward...
あ、ちょっと座員ごめんね、ごめん。クッションになってくれてありがとう。
Oh, sorry Zain, sorry. Thanks for being my cushions.
最悪、最悪クッションになってくれ。
In the worst case, just be cushions for me.
ありがとう、本当に。
Thank you, really.
あ、ちょっと待って！座員！座員！
Wait a sec! Zain! Zain!
ごめん！誰か行った？大丈夫？
Sorry! Did someone go? Are you okay?
死んだ？死んだ？大丈夫？大丈夫だった？
Did you die? Did you die? Are you okay? Were you okay?
座員クッション助かった。危なかった。
The Zain cushions saved me. That was dangerous.
みんながいなかったら文字通り大変なことになるところだったぜ。
If you all weren't here, it literally would've been a disaster.
よし。今度こそ。
Alright. This time for sure.
ま、今のでお分かりいただけただろう。どれくらい大変なことだということが。
Well, you probably understood from that just how difficult this is.
よ。あ、めっちゃ下見てない？今。
Yo. Oh, aren't I looking down a lot? Right now.
全然下見てる。座員見てる。
I'm totally looking down. Looking at the Zain.
座員見てんだ、こっち。
I'm looking at the Zain, over here.
座員見てんだ。
I'm looking at the Zain.
座員見てからよ。
After looking at the Zain...
ふぅ。踏んでない？これ。逆に。
Whew. Am I not stepping on them? Actually.
あれ？え？
Huh? Eh?
あ、これ... あ、ん？
Oh, this... Oh, hmm?
座員の上歩いてんじゃないの、これ？あれ？
Aren't I walking on top of the Zain? Huh?
これ、あれ？踏んでる？今もしかして。
Wait, am I? Am I stepping on them? Right now, maybe.
あ、踏んでるわ。ごめん。
Oh, I am. Sorry.
結構頭固いんだな。
Your heads are pretty hard.
よし。
Alright.
そして綱渡りも... 終わったー！イエーイ！
And the tightrope walk... is over! Yay!
大成功！
Huge success!
あれ？大成功だよね？
Huh? It's a huge success, right?
今度こそ大成功！
This time for sure, a huge success!
あれ？なんか...
Huh? Something's...
空気が、あれ？え？
The atmosphere is, huh? Eh?
ちょっとどう収拾つけるんですか？だめですよ、そんな空気にしちゃったら。
How are we going to fix this? You can't make the atmosphere like that.
はい、大成功。だい...
Yes, huge success. Hu...
あれ？
Huh?
よいしょ。え？ねぇ！
Heave-ho. Eh? Hey!
なんでそういうノリするの！？
Why are you acting like that!?
大成功のムード出してよ！お願いします！
Give me a huge success mood! Please!
お願いします。あ、これね、ゆくホロくるホロでは見せられなかった土下座だから。
Please. Oh, this is the dogeza I couldn't show on Yuku Holo Kuru Holo.
お願いします。大成功にしてください。みんなのコメントで、大成功にして。
Please. Make it a huge success. With everyone's comments, make it a huge success.
拍手とコメントで。ありがとうみんな。
With applause and comments. Thank you, everyone.
綱渡り、大成功！
Tightrope walk, huge success!
イエーイ！ヤッホー！
Yay! Yahoo!
あれ？
Huh?
なんかドカンパフみたいなBGMくださいよ。え？成功した、え？
Give me some 'boom-puff' BGM or something. Eh? I succeeded, eh?
嘘やん。嘘やん。
No way. No way.
まあ、いいのかこれで。本当にいいの？
Well, I guess this is okay. Is it really okay?
ありがとう。なんか、いま、もう、なんだろう、このサーカスのさ。
Thank you. Somehow, right now, I don't know, this circus...
照明音響スタッフとのいまやりとり戦いになってっから、こっち。
I'm in a battle of back-and-forth with the lighting and sound staff over here.
ちょっとゆっくりコメント見せて。
Let me see the comments for a bit.
あ、ありがとう拍手。いや、ありがとう。
Oh, thank you for the applause. No, thank you.
イエーイ、イエーイ、イエーイ。
Yay, yay, yay.
ちょっとさ、座員、座員、座員見てみたいんだよな、もうちょっと。
Hey, I want to see the Zain, Zain, Zain a bit more.
ちょっと見て。ポルカのことだけ見て今。カメラ！
Look. Look only at Polka right now. Camera!
ポルカのこと見て。
Look at Polka.
見て、見て、見て。
Look, look, look.
座員、座員写したいんや。
I want to show the Zain, Zain.
あれ？あれ？
Huh? Huh?
綱渡り消失マジック。はっ！
Tightrope disappearance magic. Ha!
消えへんな。
It's not disappearing.
見てる？ありがとう。
Are you watching? Thank you.
いまね、綱渡りをね、消そうとしてるんだけどね、どうも消えてくんねえな。
Right now, I'm trying to make the tightrope disappear, but it's not going away.
ポルカがこっち行けば、あ、いいんじゃないこれ？
If Polka goes this way... oh, isn't this good?
ということで正面に座員が！
So, in the front are the Zain!
あれ？
Huh?
いるか？
Are they there?
いるのかこれ？
Are they here?
いまどこにいる？あ、いたいたいたいた！
Where are they now? Oh, there they are!
いたいたいた！やったー！
There they are! Yay!
（笑い声）座員いたー！
(Laughs) The members were there!
いいないいな、みたいな…いいないいな…
It's good, it's good, sort of... it's good, it's good...
え、本当にいる？これ。
Wait, are they really there?
おおー、いるね。いるね。
Oh, they are here. They are here.
あ、いるじゃん。
Oh, they're here.
あ、なかなかいるね。
Oh, quite a few are here.
埋まってんね。
They're buried.
あ、しっぽも貫通したね。
Ah, the tail went through too.
あ、これいいんじゃない？
Ah, isn't this good?
お、いいね、いいね。
Oh, nice, nice.
行けた。
I made it.
（笑い声）埋もれてたね、今。
(Laughs) They were buried just now.
イエーイ、見える？
Yay, can you see?
これすごい白い光だから…あれ？あ…あ…あ…
This is a really white light... wait? Oh... oh... oh...
さよならー。あれ？
Goodbye. Wait?
さよならー！
Goodbye!
終わらないで！
Don't end!
終わらないで、まだ言いたいこといっぱいあるよ！
Don't end, I still have a lot to say!
言いたいこと…言いたいこといっぱいあるよ！
The things I want to say... I have a lot to say!
あれ？
Wait?
あのー、尾丸ポルカおるよ！
Um, Omaru Polka is here!
ポルカ！ポルカおるよ！
Polka! Polka is here!
ポルカおる。あれ？
Polka is here. Wait?
（笑い声）そういえばさ、
(Laughs) Come to think of it,
え？
Huh?
なんか、あれやね。顔とかって見せたっけ？
Like, that. Did I show you my face?
どんな顔できるか。
What kind of expressions I can make.
じゃさ、今からでもいいからさ、
So, even if it's from now,
え、もうだいぶ笑った顔とか見せたと思うんだけどさ、
Well, I think I've already shown you a lot of laughing faces, but...
何が出てくるか…はい！
What will come out... Here!
（ドラムロール）はい！
(Drum roll) Here!
あー、遅れてきた、遅れてきた…え？え？はい！
Ah, it's late, it's late... what? what? Here!
あー！今かよ！
Ah! Now?!
なんで顔に膝があるんだよ！
Why is there a kneeler on my face?!
もう一回ください、ドラムロール。
One more time please, drum roll.
（ドラムロール）っだ！
(Drum roll) There!
ポルカワワルクナイヨネー！
Polka isn't bad, is she?!
行くぞ、もう一回！えい！何が来るかなー、何が来るかな…パッ！
Here we go, one more time! Ei! What's coming, what's coming... Ba-bam!
はい、可愛い尾丸ポルカです、よろしくね、イエーイ！
Hi, I'm the cute Omaru Polka, nice to meet you, yay!
え？
Huh?
綱渡りにハード…え？
Tightrope walking in hard... what?
なんか今、え？綱渡りにハードモードってあるんですか？
Wait, what? Is there a hard mode for tightrope walking?
まあ、わかんないけど…え？
Well, I don't know, but... huh?
座員くーん！
Zain-kun!
ちょ、座員くんどういうこと？聞いてないよ！
Hey, Zain-kun, what does this mean? I didn't hear about this!
誰？用意したの！
Who? Who prepared this!
おい用意したの誰だぞい、言ってみろ！
Hey, who's the one who prepared this, speak up!
ちょ、待って待って待って！はあ？
Hey, wait wait wait! What?!
え？
Huh?
おいおいおいおい…いや、ハードってそういう…あーあー…
Whoa whoa whoa... No, hard mode is that kind of... Ahh, ahh...
え、誰用意したの？え？
Wait, who prepared this? Huh?
今名乗ればまだ間に合うよ！どうする？
If you confess now, you'll still be in time! What are you gonna do?
どうする？今…今ならまだ間に…ねえ！ねえ！
What will you do? Now... if it's now it's still... Hey! Hey!
ねえ！遠近法って言ったけど本当は遠近法じゃないから！
Hey! I said it was perspective, but it's really not perspective!
ちょ、こっからさどれくらい高いかさ、カメラで見えねえのかよ！
Wait, you can't even see how high it is from here on camera!
カメラで見えん。
You can't see it on camera.
高くね？え？え？え？え？
Isn't it high? Huh? Huh? Huh? Huh?
殺す気じゃん！
You're trying to kill me!
明日からいなくなるよ！
I'll be gone starting tomorrow!
公式ホームページクリックしたら『もっと見る』のコーナーに尾丸ポルカがいることを私は今まで喧伝してこなかったのに！
Even though I haven't been advertising that Omaru Polka is in the 'See More' section when you click on the official homepage!
ポルカ以外いるのにJP5期生のところが、おかしいよ！
There are others besides Polka in the 5th gen... something is wrong!
こんなの理不尽だよこれ、いいの？
This is so unreasonable, is this okay?
みんな、みんな、尾丸ポルカをもっと応援するポル！
Everyone, everyone, please support Omaru Polka more-pol!
よし。私ならいける。やれる。
Alright. I can do this. I can do it.
（息を飲む）
(Gasp)
いや、え、もうやばくない？これなんか。
Wait, huh, isn't this bad? This kind of thing.
え、ちょっと待ってもう…うわー！終わ…
Wait, wait a minute... whoa! It's over...
おせ、おせ、おせ、おせ、なんか聞こえてくる…
Push, push, push, push, I can hear something...
おせ、おせ、あれは何の声だ？
Push, push, whose voice is that?
おせ、おせ、おせ、おすなー、よいしょー！イエーイ！
Push, push, push, don't push... heave-ho! Yay!
フー！
Phew!
大成功ー！
Great success!
あれ？あの、せ…
Wait? Um, se...
綱渡りに挑戦！
Challenging tightrope walking!
な、大成功ー！
Wh- A great success!
あれ？
Huh?
せーの、大成功ー！
Ready, a great success!
わーいぱちぱちぱちぱち！
Yay! Clap clap clap clap!
それそれそれそれ、それ待ってた。
That's it, that's what I was waiting for.
いや、しかしこれ、高いな...
Man, but this is high...
これ、ヤバくね？
Isn't this crazy?
あれ？
Huh?
え？今まで見てたのは何だったの？
What? What was I looking at until now?
え？ちょ、あの、え？え？今だって、下に高いのが...
What? Wait, um, what? What? Just now, there was something high below...
夢？え？
A dream? Huh?
え、みんな見て...え？え？え？え？今、夢を...え？
Everyone was watching... what? What? What? What? Was I just dreaming?
夢を見てたの？今までだって、すごい綱渡りが...
Was I dreaming? Because up until now, there was a great tightrope walk...
あれ？どういうこと？
Huh? What does this mean?
だって今、踊ってポルカ、このままじゃ死んじゃうよ...
Because just now, dancing Polka was like, "I'm gonna die at this rate..."
明日から配信なくなっちゃうよ、
"My streams will be gone from tomorrow,
マリオカート大会も出られないよ、いいの？ってなってたの。
I won't even be able to enter the Mario Kart tournament, is that okay?"
まあ、何はともあれ大成功でしたー！イエーイ！
Well, anyway, it was a great success! Yay!
イエーイ、ヤッホー！あははは！
Yay! Yahoo! Ahahaha!
まあ、こんなポルカサーカスだけど、これからもよろしくお願いします。
Well, even with a Polka Circus like this, I look forward to your continued support.
え、楽しかった？
Hey, did you have fun?
色々ね、用意したんだ。
I prepared all sorts of things.
座員くんも頑張ってたし、ポルカも頑張んないと。
The Zain-kuns worked hard too, so Polka has to work hard as well.
え、何でそんな侘びられるの？
Eh? Why am I being thanked like that?
めっちゃ頑張ったよ、どや、どや！
I worked really hard, you know! How about that?
どやー！
Look at me!
よかった楽しかったんなら。ありがと、へい！
I'm glad if you had fun. Thanks! Hey!
へい、よしよしよし。
Hey! Good job, good job.
さてと、お、なんだい？お、このスポットライトさ、ちゃんとポルカに合わせて動いてる！
Well now, oh, what is it? Oh, this spotlight is actually moving along with Polka!
今気づいた！ピンスポありがと！ありがとうございます！
I just noticed! Thanks for the pin spot! Thank you very much!
すげーな。
Amazing.
え、ってことはさ、これ、これ...動いてくれてる！
Hey, so that means, this, this... it's moving for me!
よし、よし、よし、よし、はい！
Good, good, good, good, yes!
え、あ、お、生まれてきた！可愛い！
Eh? Ah! Oh! They're being born! So cute!
可愛い、これさ、なんか...え、なんか君どこから来たの？
So cute. This... wait, where did you come from?
君、どこから来た？どこに...うわぁ！生まれた！
Where did you come from? Where are you... Whoa! Another was born!
君はどこから来たの？いい子だねー。
Where did you come from? Good boy.
あ、あ、そんな引かないで引かないで、どうしたの？
Ah, ah, don't back away, don't back away. What's wrong?
な、大事、何も、何もしない、怖いこと何もしないから、どうしたの？
It's okay, I'm not doing anything. I'm not doing anything scary, so what's wrong?
いい子ね、せっかくね、一緒にね、ここまで来たんだからね、
Good boy. Since we've come this far together,
これからも一緒にやってこうね。ね？ね？
let's keep going together from now on. Right? Right?
座員くんは喋らないんです。え？
The Zain-kuns don't speak. Eh?
座員くん喋って、ほらほら、ほら、お、あれ？あれ？あれ？
Speak, Zain-kun! Come on, come on. Oh? Huh? Huh?
ちょ、ちょっと待って。え、何でそっち行っちゃうの？
Wa- Wait a second. Why are you going over there?
上手く操作できねーぜ、座員が。俺座長なのに！
I can't control the Zain-kuns very well. Even though I'm the ringmaster!
ちょ、あ、こ、こ、こ、こ、え、え、もうわかんないよ！
Wait, ah, th- th- th- th- what? What? I don't get this anymore!
座員のこと全然わかんない、お、お、お、お、お！
I don't understand the Zain-kuns at all! Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh!
デカいデカいデカいデカい！説明不要すごい！
They're big, big, big, big! No explanation needed, amazing!
これはデカすぎる！何で？
This is too big! Why?
ちょ、待って待って待って、飲み込まれるこのままじゃ！
Wait, wait, wait, wait. I'm gonna get swallowed at this rate!
ヤバい、あの、ポルカのお披露目なんです今日。
This is bad. Um, today is Polka's debut.
はい、ポルカはどこにいるでしょうかゲーム！
Okay, the "Where is Polka?" game!
ポルカはどこにいるでしょうかゲーム！
The "Where is Polka?" game!
3、2、1...
3, 2, 1...
ポルカはここです！イエーイ！わかったかな？
Polka is right here! Yay! Did you figure it out?
お前らこんな巨大化もできるんだな、初めて知った。
You guys can even grow that big, huh? I didn't know that.
え、ちょっとさこれ、座員くんちょっと、えーい！
Wait, look at this. Zain-kun, just... Hup!
あ、もっとデカくなった！
Oh, he got even bigger!
ヤバい待って、あ、ここすごい、じゅう...ぎゃー！何！？
This is bad, wait. Ah, this is intense. Cr- Gyaa! What!?
ちょっと！ここ、ポルカここ、ここ、あっ、痛っ、
Wait! Here! Polka is here! Here! Ow!
ここ、ここ、ここ。
Here! Here! Here!
あれ？あれ？座員くんにスポットライト、あの、え、見えろ、こっちか、どっちだ？
Huh? Huh? The spotlight is on Zain-kun. Um, wait, let me be seen. Is it this way? Which way is it?
ちょ、あの、あった、いたいた、
Wait, um, found it! There I am!
あっ、ここここ、ここここ。
Ah, here, here, here, here!
や、こちらはね、あの、みんなの魔法の力で座員くん増えてるから...
Well, you see, the Zain-kuns are multiplying thanks to everyone's magic...
あっ、ちょ、まだここ空いてるよ。
Ah, wait, there's still a spot open here.
まだここ空いてるよ、まだここ空いてるよ...
There's still a spot here, still a spot here...
あー！空いてないよー！
Aah! There's no spot!
くっ、こ、あ、あー！何で、まだいける、まだいける。
Ugh, th- Ah, aah! Why? I can still do it, I can still do it.
あー、ふぅ、え？あ、だんだんちっちゃく...
Ah... Phew. Huh? Oh, they're gradually getting smaller...
あ、もうそろそろ時間だよ座長、って教えてくれてるんだ。ありがとう。
Oh, they're telling me, "It's almost time, ringmaster." Thank you.
やっぱ...
Actually...
時間ってすげえ助かるな。
Time is a huge help.
もう時間だよって。
It's saying it's time.
さて！
Well then!
パンッ！
*Clap!*
さあ、ここまでやっておいて、
Now, after getting this far,
えーっと、何もないのは...
um, it wouldn't do to have nothing...
ちょっと、言い方が分かんなくなっちゃったんだけど。
Wait, I forgot how to say it.
えーっと、ぜひポルカサーカスの、お土産に1つこちらがどうでしょうか。
Um, how about one of these as a souvenir from Polka Circus?
あ、はい！
Ah, yes!
本日ポルカサーカスでお土産も販売しております！
Souvenirs are also on sale today at Polka Circus!
というわけで、こちら！
And so, here they are!
ババーン！お待たせしました！3D化記念グッズ発売！
Ta-da! Thanks for waiting! 3D Commemoration Goods on sale!
はい、パフパフ〜、キャッキャッキャッ。
Yes, honk honk~, yay!
これね、アクリルスタンド、
We have an acrylic stand,
ラバーストラップ、しっぽの形、
a rubber strap in the shape of a tail,
おまる座公演チケット風パスケース！
and an Omaru-za performance ticket-style pass case!
これすごいで、見れば分かるけどすごいで。
These are great; you'll see just how great they are.
見れば分かるけど、すごいで。
You'll know what I mean once you see them.
ん〜、えーっとページが開かれたのかな？できてるかな？
Hmm, um, has the page opened? Is it ready?
なんかね、ページのオープンはしてるけど、
It seems the page is open, but...
販売自体は21時からです、よろしくお願いします！
sales actually start at 9:00 PM, so please look forward to it!
なので見ましょう！実際、あ、待って、見ない待って！
So let's see! Actually, ah wait, don't look, wait!
水飲むわ。
I'm going to drink some water.
うー、あぶねーあぶねー。
Whew, close one, close one.
水飲み忘れるとこだったわ。
I almost forgot to drink water.
え？
Eh?
あ、水飲んでる。
Ah, I'm drinking water.
え？一回閉めて？
Eh? Close it for a bit?
あの、一回、一回、ちょっと...
Um, just once, just once...
あの、一回閉めてー！
Um, close the curtains!
あぶねー。
That was close.
舞台裏が見られるとこだったぜ。
You almost saw backstage.
はい、というわけでね、お待たせしました！
Yes, and so, thanks for waiting!
はい、というわけでこちらが、実際のアクリルスタンドになってます。
Yes, so this is the actual acrylic stand.
これ、あ、あ、えーっとどうやって写真撮ったっけ？
This, uh, how did I take the photo again?
こうやってたので写真撮って...
I was doing this when they took the photo...
しぇー、しぇーになってるな、こっちが多分こうで、こうして、こう！
Sheeeh! It's a 'Sheeeh' pose. This side is probably like this, then this, then this!
え、近くないこれ？あ、いいんじゃない？なかなかいいいい。
Wait, isn't it close? Ah, isn't it good? Pretty good, good, good.
近いポーズになりました！
I got the pose close enough!
どうでしょう、どやぁ。
What do you think? Ta-da!
でもこっちは帽子が取れて、帽子をバーンと見せてるから、
But here the hat is off and I'm showing it off, so...
なかなかいいんじゃない？
isn't it pretty good?
これ大きさも何センチ？
How many centimeters is this?
まあ大きい、そこそこデカい。
Well, it's big. Quite large.
えーっと、140ミリです。
Um, it's 140 millimeters.
140ミリは14センチです、分かるかな？
140mm is 14cm. Do you get it?
オッケー、じゃあ14センチのアクリルスタンドと、こちら！
Okay, so the 14cm acrylic stand and, this!
はいこれ見て！見てこれ！見てちょっと！
Yes, look at this! Look at this! Just look!
ちょっとこれ見て！
Just look at this!
やばくない？
Isn't it crazy?
かわいい！かわいい！
So cute! So cute!
これにはプロデューサーも納得。あ、はい、えーっと、
The producer is also satisfied with this. Ah, yes, um,
しっぽラバーストラップ&おまる座公演チケット風パスケースです！
the tail rubber strap & Omaru-za performance ticket-style pass case!
よくできました！
Well done!
これね、分かるかな？
This, can you see?
おまるぽるかって書いてある下にちゃんと「ポルカおるか？」って書いてある！
Under where it says 'Omaru Polka', it says 'Polka Oruka?' (Is Polka here?)
これはなかなかいいよね！
This is pretty good, right!
で、ページはできてるから販売開始は9時から！
The page is ready, so sales start at 9:00 PM!
チェ、チェ、チェ、チェキラ！いいいい、なかなか、お、いいんじゃない？
Che-che-che-check it out! Good, good, pretty... oh, isn't it good?
これは普通のあれでしょ？
This is just standard, right?
サイズはあの普通の、なんか定期が入る、えーっと...
The size is just standard, like a pass holder, um...
100×70、多分そんな、
100x70. Probably something like that.
あの名刺じゃなくて、定期券が入るサイズ。
Not business card size, but the size for a commuter pass.
で、ラバーストラップこちらが、40ミリ×80ミリ。
And the rubber strap here is 40mm x 80mm.
なんかね、ポルカも見たけど、こ、これぐらい！
Polka saw it too, and it's like... about this much!
あの、これ個人の感想です。個人の感想です、これぐらい、こんな感じ。
Um, this is just my personal impression. Personal impression, like this much, this kind of feeling.
これぐらい！
About this much!
で、ポルカさっき気づいたんだけどこれさ、一緒に付けちゃえば...
And, Polka just realized, if you attach these together...
尻尾ラバーストラップ ＆ 「おまる座公演チケット風」パスケース
Tail Rubber Strap & "Omaru-za Ticket Style" Pass Case
いいんじゃない？
Isn't it good?
あ、実はこれさ、セット販売とさ、単品販売あるよね、確か。
Oh, actually, I believe there's a set sale and individual sales for this.
全部グッズセット、全部セットと...
There's a full goods set, a complete set...
...単品販売があるから、好きな方...
...and individual sales, so whichever you like...
全部セットが4000円で、
The full set is 4,000 yen,
それぞれ買うと2000円です。
and if you buy them individually, they're 2,000 yen each.
一緒に付けんの、あれ、可愛いですよ。
It's cute to wear them together.
いや、あれでほら、帽子のとことさ、尻尾のとこバラバラになってっからこれ。
Look, the hat part and the tail part are separate on this.
くっついてないよ、これちゃんとバラバラになってるから。
They're not attached, they're properly separated.
見えるでしょ？可愛くない？
You can see it, right? Isn't it cute?
パスケースはね、これね、裏地もね、凝ってるから。
For the pass case, even the lining is detailed.
あ、裏地の絵、出てないんだこれ。
Oh, the lining picture isn't shown here.
裏地もね、色がね、ちゃんと付いとるんよ。
The lining has colors properly applied too.
買って、見て、写真とかね。
Buy it and check it out, like in photos.
あ、今、概要欄に多分URLがザインパワーで貼られてると思うんで。
Oh, right now, the URL is probably posted in the description box by Zain-power.
終わったら、買っちゃってください、そしてTwitterで報告し合おう。イェーイ！
Please buy it after this is over, and let's report to each other on Twitter. Yay!
あ、もう一回。あだ、呟いとこう。ハッシュタグ、#尾丸ポルカ3D。イェーイ！
Oh, once more. Ah, let's tweet it. Hashtag, #OmaruPolka3D. Yay!
ちょっとザイン君、喋ってて。ちょっと水飲むわ。
Zain-kun, talk for a bit. I'm gonna drink some water.
ザインどこ水？この辺り？
Zain, where's the water? Around here?
あ、美味しいわ。
Ah, that's delicious.
あ、ザイン君喋んないんだっけ？そっか。
Oh, Zain-kun doesn't talk? I see.
ん？ん？ん？ん？
Hmm? Hmm? Hmm? Hmm?
いなくなった。どうしよう。え？え？
He's gone. What should I do? Eh? Eh?
あ、もう時間。あ。
Oh, it's time already. Ah.
ポルカとしたことがうっかり忘れちまってたぜ！
For someone like Polka, I had completely forgotten!
まあ、いろいろやってきたけど、今日は最後に、ついに...
Well, I've done various things, but today, finally...
この歌が歌えればホロライブだとポルカ思っておりました。
Polka thought that if I could sing this song, I'd be a true Hololive member.
歌わせてください。
Please let me sing it.
いきなりいくよ！
Here we go, straight into it!
「Shiny Smily Story」
Shiny Smily Story
同じ未来を見ていたい
I want to keep seeing the same future
あの夢手にしたい
I want to grasp that dream
それそれ違った心で
With our each different hearts
走れどー！
Let's run!
はい！はい！はい！はいはい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai-hai!
どこ見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
It sprouted in a place where everywhere I looked was pitch black
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
My eyes were captivated by that tiny bit of hope
不安で揺れる心 歌うチューニングして
My heart trembling with anxiety, tuning it into a song
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていいさよ
It's okay to squeeze out that tiny bit of courage
諦めろ文字デリートして進む
Delete the word 'give up' and move forward
苦しい時ももう私は
Even when it's painful, I am
一人じゃないから！ 行くぞ！
Not alone anymore! Here we go!
だからもっと夢追いかけたい
So I want to chase my dreams even more
ワクワク止まらない
The excitement won't stop
想像超えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world that exceeds your imagination
アクセスしてみたい
I want to try to access it
後悔なんてさせない
I won't let you regret anything
それそれ違った心で
With our each different hearts
走れどー！
Let's run!
裾の空に輝く眩しい思いは
The dazzling thoughts shining in the bottom of the sky
見たことのない光を見合う瞳溶けるよう
Melting into eyes that gaze at a light never seen before
いつも聞こえるメロはここにキャッチして
Catch the melody always heard right here
また新しい光を探したくなるよ
Making me want to search for a new light again
君の笑顔を保存して進む
I'll save your smile and move forward
悲しい時に見返すよ
I'll look back at it when I'm sad
力が湧くから！ フゥー！
Because it gives me strength! Woo!
胸を張って夢追いかけたい
I want to chase my dreams with pride
奇跡のストーリー
A story of miracles
一緒に作ろう終わらない夢を
Let's create a never-ending dream together
誰一人欠かせない相まったこの世界
In this world where everyone is indispensable
それそれ違った心で
With our each different hearts
彩れー！
Color it in!
はい！はい！はい！はいはい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai-hai!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
あの日誓った気持ち
The feelings I pledged that day
伝えあえるものがある
Are something we can share with each other
忘れずにこの鼓動
Without forgetting this heartbeat
鳴らし続けたい
I want to keep it pounding
終わらない世界に
Into this never-ending world
あふれ出すよ
They will overflow
笑顔たち
All the many smiles
あこがれの舞台立ちたい
I want to stand on the stage I've longed for
らしく輝きたい
I want to shine in my own way
時になみだして
Sometimes I'll shed tears
また笑いあいたい
But I want to laugh together again
同じ未来を見たい
I want to see the same future
あの夢手にしたい
I want to grasp that dream
踏み出そう
Let's take a step
奇跡の一歩を
Toward a miracle
Ah! 夢の舞台
Ah! The stage of dreams
ワクワク止まらない
My excitement won't stop
想像超えてゆく
Going beyond imagination
世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world
アクセスしてみてな
Try accessing it
後悔なんてここにない
There's no regret here
それぞれ違った
Each and every unique
踊る手叩くわ
Clapping our dancing hands
ありがとう！
Thank you!
尾丸ポルカでした！
I was Omaru Polka!
ポルカここにおるよ！
Polka is right here!
これからもよろしくね！
Please continue to support me!
ううー！
Woo!
いぇーい！
Yeah!
やっほーい！
Yahoo!
ううー！
Woo!
尾丸ポルカ 3Dお披露目
Omaru Polka 3D Debut